As countries worldwide
那是一个信息战的时代
battle discrete yet fierce information warfare,
世界各国各自为营 为信息展开激烈竞争
two countries are at a standoff.
其中有两个国家僵持不下
Ostania in the east, and Westalis in the west.
东方的东国跟西方的西国
Westalis launched Operation Strix to find out the movements
为了查清东国政府重要人物的动向
of key figures
西国开始了
in the Ostanian government, who are plotting a war.
“枭”行动
Highly-skilled Agent Twilight, was put in charge of the operation.
这项任务由技艺超群的特工黄昏负责
The man with 100 different faces, was given a mission
这名面孔千变万化的男人 收到了一项任务
to create a family.
就是组建家庭
Father, Loid Forger, a psychiatrist.
父亲 劳埃德福杰 是一名心理医师
His true identity is spy. Codenamed Twilight.
他的真实身分是间谍 代号“黄昏”
Mother, Yor Forger, a city hall employee.
母亲 约尔福杰 是市政厅公务员
Her true identity is assassin. Codenamed Thorn Princess.
她的真实身分是职业杀手 代号“荆棘公主”
Daughter, Anya Forger.
女儿 阿尼亚福杰
Her true identity is being a telepath who can read minds.
真实身分是具有读心术的超能力者
Dog, Bond Forger.
宠物犬 邦德福杰
A psychic canine that can glimpse the future.
是一只能够预知未来的超能力狗狗
For their own personal interests, they created a fake family.
他们为了各自的利益 组成了虚假的家庭
The mission continues, as three of them hide their identities from each other.
在彼此互相隐瞒真实身分的情况下 持续进行任务
ORIGINAL WORK BY TATSUYA ENDO SERIALIZED ON SHUEISHA'S SHONEN JUMP PLUS
(远藤达哉原创作品 连载于集英社漫画杂志《SHONEN JUMP PLUS》)
Yes.
是
The service has been completed.
已经招待完毕了
No, I will head home right away.
不 我会马上回家
Since my husband asked me to pick up some
因为丈夫交代我在回去的路上
milk and eggs on the way back.
去买牛奶跟鸡蛋
Damn it. She's the infamous assassin.
可恶 她就是恶名昭彰的杀手
- She's Thorn Princess! - Yes, thank you.
-荆棘公主! -好 谢谢您
Die, you monster!
怪物 去死吧!
MISSION:26 FOLLOW MAMA AND PAPA
剧名:任务:26 跟踪父亲与母亲吧
We have breaking news.
刚刚收到一则新闻快报
Several bodies believed to belong to members of Red Circus
在北区一处建筑物内发现
were found inside a building in the Northern District.
许多红色马戏团成员的尸体
- Red Circus is... - Father.
-红色马戏团是... -父亲
I want to watch anime.
阿尼亚想看卡通
- News is boring. - No.
-新闻好无聊 -不行
There's a load of information
光是一个公开的新闻频道
to gain from a single news bulletin released to the public.
就可以获得大量情报
Fine.
知道了
You can change the channel.
你可以换频道
Good morning, Bondman.
早上好 邦德曼
Your mission today is to tail a certain target.
你今天的任务是跟踪特定目标人物
- Find out where... - How exciting!
-找出... -好兴奋!
the secret weapons are hidden,
...秘密武器的藏匿地点
- and destroy them. - I'm home.
-然后摧毁掉 -我到家了
Welcome home, Yor.
欢迎回来 约尔小...
These are...
这里是...
the milk and eggs.
你要的牛奶跟鸡蛋
Oh... Thank you.
好...谢谢你
Are you feeling unwell?
那个 你是不是哪里不舒服?
No, it's nothing like that. I'm just a little...
不是的 没什么 我只是有点...
There's no way I can tell him!
我怎么说得出口!
I can't tell him that I'm in a lot of pain
我在跟武装势力对战时
because I got shot in the butt during a fight
屁股被枪打到 所以疼得要命
with a group of armed militants!
这种事哪能说出来!
I treated the wound, but still...
虽然已经处理过伤口 但...
Guns?! She got shot by a gun!
枪?被子弹打到了!
Mother. Are you going to die?
母亲...会死掉吗?
Don't worry, Anya. I won't die.
不用担心 阿尼亚 我不会死的
I'm a little tired, so I'll head to bed now.
我有点累 就先上床睡觉了
I'm sure I'll feel better
只要好好睡一觉
after a good night's sleep, right?
想必感觉就会好多了
Yor was in a bad mood. Was it because I asked her to go shopping?
约尔小姐不高兴了 是因为我拜托她去买东西吗?
That must be it! This marriage is just on paper,
一定是这样的 毕竟只是契约婚姻
but I've been asking her to do so much! That must've made her unhappy!
我却对她要求那么多 她一定是为此感到不高兴!
Mother won't die even when she gets shot by a gun! Impressive!
母亲被枪打到也不会死 好厉害喔!
This is not good! Not good at all! Family troubles will ruin this mission!
糟糕了 完蛋了! 家庭失和会导致任务失败!
I must do everything within my power to fix this!
我必须竭尽所能挽救婚姻关系!
Father's way off.
父亲错得离谱
Hopefully she'll feel better after a night's sleep.
希望她睡一觉起来 心情会好一点
- It's not better. - She's not better.
-心情没有变好 -伤口没有变好
Good morning.
早上好
It hurts.
好疼
I need to do something to lift her mood.
必须做点什么让她心情变好
Yor, today is our day off.
约尔小姐 今天我们休假
- So, will you go out on a date with me? - Date...
-要不要跟我出去约会呢? -约会...
You're always helping me by taking care of the house and looking after Anya.
一直以来家务事 跟阿尼亚都多亏有你费心
So I want you to relax and let loose today.
所以我希望 至少今天你可以好好放松一下
A date...
约会...
My boyfriend took me on a cruise for our date the other day.
前天我男朋友带我去游艇约会了
What kind of dates do you go on, Yor?
约尔前辈都怎么约会呢?
- We've never gone on a date. - Liar.
-我们没约会过 -骗人
It's normal to go on dates even after you get married.
婚后去约会也是稀松平常的事吧
Oh... well...
不...那个...
I should probably gain some experience of going on a date,
我应该要增加约会方面的经验
or people might suspect that we're not really a married couple.
不然可能会被怀疑是假结婚
We don't have to go if you're not feeling well.
要是你身体不舒服的话就不用勉强了
I will go!
我要去!
This is a great opportunity, so I will use this chance to learn!
如此难得的机会 我一定会妥善利用 善加学习
Learn?
学习?
I'll get dressed right away!
我马上去换衣服!
Anya wants to go too! A date! How exciting!
阿尼亚也想去!约会 好兴奋!
Sorry. You're not coming with us. It's a date, after all.
抱歉 你不能跟来 毕竟这是约会
How sad.
真难过
Have fun at home.
好好在家里玩吧
Come here.
借一步说话
Listen up! How many times do I have to tell you?
听好了 到底要我说几次啊?
I'm your informant! Not someone you call for odd jobs!
我是情报员!不是什么打杂跑腿的!
I have no choice. I can't leave Anya home all by herself.
没办法啊 我不能把阿尼亚一个人留在家里
This is an important part of the mission to keep the family together.
为了守护家庭的团结和谐 这也是重要的任务之一啊
You said you want to invent some new spying gadgets, right?
你不是说你想开发新的间谍道具吗?
This payment will help with that.
这点报酬可以帮到你
You keep on using my weakness against me!
你老是抓着我的软肋不放!
All right. Shall we go, Yor?
好 那我们就出发吧 约尔小姐
Your hand, please.
我牵你吧
Last night, I came up with 862 date plans
昨天晚上我构想了862种
that Yor might enjoy.
约尔小姐会喜欢的约会方案
I'm all set.
绝对万无一失
I'm sorry, Loid.
不好意思 劳埃德先生
I'll sustain more damage to my butt if I have to sit!
坐下来的话 会加重屁股的伤势!
I'd like to walk on our date.
我想用走的去约会
She's mad? She's still mad?
她生气了?是还在生气吗?
Dammit. That takes out 794 date plans.
可恶 这样一来有794种都白想了
Good idea.
说...说得也是
Let's just take it easy and go for a stroll.
那我们就轻松地散步过去吧
I'm worried about Father and Mother.
好担心父亲跟母亲
That guy's hopeless if he's got a little kid worrying about him.
居然让这么小的孩子担心他 那家伙也真是没救了
Little kids should go inside and watch anime.
小孩子就该乖乖待在家里看卡通
Go, Bondman! Tail the target, and maintain world peace!
去吧 邦德曼! 跟踪目标人物 维护世界和平吧!
Scruffy!
鸟窝头!
Anya wants to tail Father and Mother.
阿尼亚想跟踪父亲跟母亲
What? That sounds like so much fun!
什么?听起来就超好玩的!
- Shall we do it? - Let's tail them!
-行动吧? -追踪!
Your dad is pretty sharp.
你爸直觉非常敏锐
So let's disguise ourselves, and be careful. Go change!
我们要变装一下 行事要谨慎 去换衣服!
Yes, sir!
好的!
That outfit makes you stand out even more.
你那身打扮反而看起来更显眼
- No problem. - If you say so.
-“谋”问题 -是这样吗?
You're in charge of guarding the house,
看家的任务就交给你们了
my capable agents of the secret organization P2. Bond,
我秘密组织P2能干的特工邦德
Director Kimera,
奇美拉指挥官
and Agent Penguin Man.
还有特工企鹅曼
Hey Twilight,
哼哼 黄昏先生
you've charmed countless women with your art of seduction.
至今以来 你善用各种花招迷倒无数女性
This is my chance to see you in action!
这次正好让我见识一番!
He's too far. I can't read his mind.
太远了 读不到心
What are they doing?
他们在干嘛?
CAUGHT WITHIN SECONDS
(几秒钟内就发现了)
Are they pretending to be spies?
是在玩间谍过家家吗?
What's so fun about that?
好玩的地方在哪?
I'll view this as part of my mission to maintain a happy family,
我就当作为了 圆满维持家庭和谐的任务
and pretend I don't notice them.
假装没看到他们好了
And Anya should be safe as long as Franky is with her.
而且阿尼亚 只要有弗兰克跟在旁边就很安全
- Loid? - Oh, it's nothing.
-劳埃德先生? -没事 没什么
More importantly, I have to lift Yor's mood.
目前更重要的是 让约尔小姐的心情变好
Shall we do some shopping?
去购物中心逛逛吧?
Yor, you have a nice figure, so I bet you'll look good in pants too.
约尔小姐 你身材很好 想必穿裤装也会很好看
Would you like to try it on?
要不要试穿看看呢?
If I wear anything that tight,
如果穿那么紧的话
it'll put pressure on my wound, and the pain will make me faint.
就会压到伤口 我会痛晕过去的
Not a chance.
我不行
Sorry.
对不起
MOVIE THEATER
(电影院)
Oh, my love!
噢 我的爱!
- Look into my eyes and tell me it's a lie! - Yor...
-看着我的双眼 告诉我这是谎言! -约尔小姐...
Why don't you sit? You're attracting attention.
这样蛮引人注目的 要不要坐着看呢?
No thanks.
不用 我站着就好
If I sit, my butt...
坐下来的话 我的屁股...
CLUB
(爵士俱乐部)
Yor, it's dangerous, so you should sit.
约尔小姐 这样很危险 还是坐下比较好
But if I sit, my butt...
可是坐下来的话 我的屁股...
SPA
(SPA)
My butt...
我的屁股...
ZOO
(动物园)
What am I to do?
该怎么办才好?
I can't concentrate on this date at all!
我完全无法专心约会!
Even though Loid is teaching me so many things!
难得劳埃德先生教我那么多东西!
What should I do?
怎么办?
Not only have I not lifted her mood, I've made it worse!
不要说心情变好了 反而还变得更糟!
Did I pick all the wrong choices?
难道我选错方案吗?
What is it? What does Yor like? Did I not do enough research?
是什么?约尔小姐究竟喜欢什么? 是我调查得还不够吗?
Loid is always acting so cool, but he's failing so badly!
劳埃德那家伙平常总爱耍帅 但现在完全不行嘛!
How pathetic!
实在是逊毙了!
Scruffy, are you a mean person?
鸟窝头 原来你是坏蛋吗?
Not at all! I have the right to sneer because I can't get any girls!
才不是!作为万年单身狗 这点嘲笑的权力我还是有的!
- How pitiful. - What did you say?!
-真可怜 -你说什么?
They're so obtrusive.
他们好碍眼
I'm sure you're tired. How about dinner?
我想你也累了吧 要不要去吃晚饭呢?
Sure.
好啊
Mr. Forger, we have your reservation.
是事先预约的福杰先生吧
Please sit.
请坐
We're very sorry, sir.
真的很抱歉 先生
We do not serve customers
本店谢绝
in casual clothes, nor children.
穿便装的客人
- No one under the age of 18. - You heard the man.
-以及未满十八岁者 -听到了吧?
Let's give up.
放弃吧
Let's head back soon.
差不多该回去了
I was getting a little bored anyway.
反正我也开始觉得无聊了
Thorn Princess? Why is she here?
荆棘公主?她为什么会在这里?
What is it?
怎么了?
Are you looking for a bathroom?
你要上厕所吗?
No doubt about it!
绝对不会错的!
That hurts!
好疼!
She's the assassin that raided our hideout yesterday!
是昨天突袭我们基地的那个女人!
What is she doing here?
她在这里干嘛?
I felt God's mercy as the lone survivor of that horrendous event,
我以为我在那惨剧中一人生还 是出自老天爷的怜悯
and that made me want to
因此为了女朋友
straighten out my life, and work hard for the sake of my girlfriend!
我正想金盆洗手重新做人 好好工作
But I see, this is a command from my friends in hell.
我懂了 这是已去的故人给我的命令
You guys want me to kill her, right? I'll avenge the Red Circus!
你们想要我干掉她吧? 我会替红色马戏团报仇的!
There's a bad guy in the restaurant!
餐厅有坏人!
Die, Thorn Princess!
去死吧 荆棘公主!
Whoa, you're the great assassin after all! You win!
真不愧是最强的职业杀手!你赢了!
Yor, you're an assassin?
约尔小姐 你竟然是杀手?
Let's split. No more Forger family. We'll dump Anya too.
离婚吧 没有福杰一家了 阿尼亚也不要了
- Let's go, little one. - No!
-走啦 小不点 -不行!
What? You still want to continue this?
什么?你还想继续玩下去吗?
My family's in trouble!
有家族危机!
What?
什么?
Hold on a second.
等一下
Is this kid worried that her parents might divorce?
这家伙难道是在担心爸妈会离婚吗?
She's so invested, even though they're a fake family.
明明是伪装的家人 她居然担心成这样
I guess I have no choice. I'll help you out for a little longer.
真...真是拿你没办法 我就勉强再陪你玩一下
- Now it's time to play "infiltration." - Infiltration!
-好 这次来玩潜入游戏吧 -潜入!
What would you like as your aperitif?
两位想点什么开胃酒呢?
I'll have a dry champagne.
我要来点干型香槟
I'll just have a cocktail.
我的话鸡尾酒就可以了
This restaurant serves
这家餐厅
a rare pufferfish dish that comes from the Far East.
有很稀罕的远东河豚料理喔
It's part of the meal today.
今天的菜单上有喔
Oh, I see.
是这样吗?
Pufferfish is a fish that carries a toxic poison,
河豚是种有毒鱼类
but its flesh is delicious.
但肉质很鲜美
Excuse me, please take this to the lady at table three.
不好意思 这是三号桌的女士点的
- Okay. - Gulp down that pufferfish poison.
-好 -吞下那杯河豚毒
And go to hell, Thorn Princess!
然后上西天吧 荆棘公主!
Hurry up, Scruffy!
快一点 鸟窝头!
Don't rush. Infiltration requires patience.
别催我 潜入行动要慎重才行
If you make a fuss, you'll get caught.
太过慌张的话会被抓到哦
Thank you for waiting.
让您久等了
Wow, what a surprising color and aroma.
总觉得这颜色跟味道很不得了
It's so thick.
好浓稠喔
You can't drink it, Mother!
母亲 不可以喝那个!
Oh... I feel...
奇怪 我感觉...
I successfully avenged all of you, my friends.
同志们 我替大家报仇了
The pain in my butt is gone now, and I feel so much better!
屁股的疼痛感没了 感觉轻松多了
The woman had a high tolerance for poison.
女人拥有超强的耐毒性
My body feels a little tingly, but I can sit down!
虽然全身有点麻麻的 但我能坐下了
I'm so hungry now. I can't wait to try the dishes.
感觉肚子好饿喔 真期待待会上桌的料理
Oh... yes.
是...是啊
She's in a good mood now. Is it because of the alcohol?
她心情变好了 是因为酒的缘故?
What? Wait... I gave her the blood... What?
怪了 我给了她河豚血啊...怎么会?
PUFFERFISH POISON IS DANGEROUS. DON'T TRY IT.
(河豚毒性很危险 请勿尝试)
There's a fine line between poison and medicine.
毒物与药物仅一线之隔
Normal people must follow directions, and the recommended dosages.
常人请遵照指示的用法用量服用
What's wrong?
怎么了?
I'll have to resort to extreme measures.
我必须采取极端手段了
I'll personally kill and bury her!
我就亲手埋了你吧!
I can make an improvised bomb with the tools in the storeroom.
用仓库中的工具 可以做出简易的炸弹
I'll use that, that, and that.
用这个、这个还有那个
I can't place a timing device,
没办法做出时间限制装置
so I'll have to carry it there myself.
只能自己带在身上拿过去了
I'm sorry, Catherine. Please forgive this fool.
对不起 凯瑟琳 原谅我这个笨蛋吧
We're almost right above the dining area.
就快到用餐区域的上方了
Once we're right above them, I'll lower you with a wire,
一旦到了他们上方 我就用钢丝放你下去
so that you can hear their conversation... Wait...
你就能听到他们的对话...人呢?
I should be able to make the bomb casing, by using *** and ***.
用XXX跟XXX 应该就能做出炸弹容器
I think it was placed on the right shelf.
我记得是放在右边的架子上
After I put in the blue ♪ located across the shelf,
然后把那边架子上的XXX 加进去之后
I'll *** it. I'll also have to
我得XXX 然后还得
add ***, to make it extra lethal.
加入XXX 这样杀伤力会更强大
Yup, I can do it!
很好 我办得到!
What the hell is this?
这什么东西?
Olive oil? Who the hell dropped this here?
橄榄油?到底是谁把油倒在这里?
Dammit. I don't have time for this!
可恶 现在不是 被这种鸟事绊住的时候!
Who the hell is setting up these pranks?
这些恶作剧到底是谁搞的?
This is the perfect container to place the bomb in.
这个刚好可以拿来装炸弹
No, this is a little too small.
不行 这个有点太小了
Wait, is this...
等等 这个难道...
Why was there an actual bomb in here?
里面怎么会有做好的炸弹?
And what is this? Peanuts?
还有这是什么?花生?
Peanut bomb?
花生炸弹吗?
Don't tell me...
难道...
Is this Thorn Princess's crony?
是荆棘公主的...同伴?
A child?
小孩子?
Red Circus guy.
红色马戏团的家伙
She knows who I am!
她知道我是谁!
From now on, don't ever come near Anya--
从今往后再也不要靠近阿尼亚...
I mean, us, ever again.
我是说再也不要靠近我们
Got it? This is your last chance.
懂了没?没有下一次了
You should quit this bad guy business
你应该好好改过自新 重新做人
and make Catherine happy.
让凯瑟琳幸福吧
She knows about Catherine too!
她居然连凯瑟琳的事都知道!
She knows everything.
一切都被看穿了吗?
Thorn Princess cannot be underestimated.
真是不能小看荆棘公主
She even has a talented child like that working for her.
她居然有那么厉害的小孩子替她工作
She's on a completely different level. I'm no match for her.
她跟我根本不是同一个水平 我不是她的对手
I'll forget everything and live a normal life.
忘掉一切 过平凡人的生活吧
That restaurant was rather hectic, wasn't it?
那家餐厅还真是吵闹呢
But it was delicious!
可是东西好好吃!
It sure was.
说得是呢
What a relief. She seems to be in a better mood now.
太好了 她看起来心情好多了
There's peace once again in the Forger household.
福杰家再度重拾和平了
It's all thanks to Anya.
这都是阿尼亚的功劳
Where did you run off to a while ago?
你刚刚跑去哪了?
Thank you very much, Loid.
真的非常谢谢你 劳埃德先生
Ever since I was young, I had to work and take care of my younger brother,
我从小就必须赚钱并照顾弟弟
so I never had time to have fun.
所以从来没有时间出来玩
That's why
所以...
I really enjoyed myself today.
今天我真的非常开心
Please invite me out again.
请你下次再邀我出去吧
When I'm not injured.
在我没受伤的时候
It'd be my pleasure.
这是我的荣幸
Look at that! It's a fairground!
快看那边 是露天游乐场!
Should we stop by?
要顺路过去玩玩吗?
Father! Anya wants to ride the Ferris wheel!
父亲 阿尼亚想坐摩天轮!
- A fairground! - Hey, stop that!
-露天游乐场! -喂 快停下来!
Are we not tailing them anymore?
跟踪呢?结束了吗?
Why?
怎么会?
The medicine, or poison in this case, wore off.
药效 或者该说毒性已经解除了
I don't understand women.
我真是不懂女人心
MISSION:27 PART A: DAMIAN'S FIELD RESEARCH TRIP
(任务:27 A Part:达米安的野外学习)
PART B: BOND'S STRATEGY TO STAY ALIVE
(B Part:彭德的生存战略)
Subtitle translation by: Lili Morita
字幕翻译:洪贞韵